Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
Kimi yo hashire
You must run forth!
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Kyodai na teki o
You must fight the towering foe!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Kimi yo tsukame
You must seize the power!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
A half-century has passed since humanity began moving...
...its burgeoning population into space.
These gigantic space colonies orbiting the Earth...
...became a second home to humanity...
...where people were born and raised...
...and where they died.
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
The colonies of Side 3 proclaimed themselves
the Principality of Zeon.
It launched a war of independence
against the Earth Federation.
During this war, the Principality of Zeon
and the Federation...
...caused the deaths
of half the total population.
Humanity was horrified by its own actions.
Winds of War
W-We're going to hit it!
Is someone on the sub-bridge?
Coaly, you're a big boy, aren't you?
You mustn't cry over something like this.
Look. This is Earth.
This is where your father grew up.
Your father was a wonderful man
who you can be proud of.
Are mothers all like that?
I guess you haven't seen
your mother in a long while.
But...
Amuro, Bright is calling you.
Okay. Haro.
This is reckless, Mr. Bright! Fly higher!
Don't you see that up there?
I wish we could skim closer to the ground.
But our pilot doesn't have
the necessary skills!
I can do it.
This is Bison. The Trojan Horse
is attempting to cross the mountain range.
Don't let them advance any further.
Once you join the Magella Attacks
on the ground, open fire.
Garma.
What is it, Char?
Why do you think the Trojan Horse
is flying like that?
To hide from our radar.
That's not it.
They're setting up an interference field using
the terrain and Minovsky particles.
Like so.
Then the effect of
the Minovsky particles is magnified.
However powerful,
our guided weapons are useless.
We've got to ambush them in a place
where we have the advantage.
And then we overwhelm them.
What does this mean?
The Dopp formations are withdrawing.
Something's going on.
We're in the Great Canyon.
The White Base is here right now.
The enemy will probably amass
their forces near Mid Lake here.
I agree.
It's because that will be
the most disadvantageous point for us.
Our fate will depend
on the success of the Gundam.
Amuro, we're counting on you.
Right.
Apparently it doesn't matter what we do.
Mr. Kai!
Sorry.
Fraw Bow, who are these people?
Lieutenant. They insist
on having a word with you.
Actually...
We want you to leave us here.
What?! Leave you?!
But we're in a combat situation!
St. Anges, a town near here...
...is my husband's home town.
Home town? Never thought I'd hear
a word like that in this situation.
I understand that it's difficult.
But I want to bring up my son
where his father grew up.
You people!
How can you say such selfish things?!
Bright?
Sir. I have an idea.
An idea?
Yes. We suggest a ceasefire to the Zeons,
and let these people off.
What do you think, Char?
About them wanting a ceasefire
so they can drop off refugees?
I don't like it.
However...
Hm?
I don't know what the enemy's thinking...
...but this can buy us some time.
And...?
This could be our chance to reinforce
our slow-moving ground forces.
And that will increase our chance of victory.
All right!
It seems his privileged boyhood
has spoiled him. He's too soft.
Why are you breaking it?
What a waste.
Shut up! We're blowing a hole in it
to fool the enemy!
We'll definitely win this time!
If we don't win, it'll prove your incompetence.
There's no turning back now. Are you sure?
My mind is made up.
No matter what happens,
I want to raise my son on the Earth.
I suppose you can't understand my feelings.
I've never really lived on Earth, after all.
Here it comes.
Right on schedule.
This is Big John.
I have a visual on the White Base transport.
Anything unusual?
Seems the side of the craft was hit by a shell.
So, that's our escort?
Hi!
Hey, stop it!
Are you jealous?
That's not it.
I'm just worried about the plan.
Captain, a child is waving at us.
Yeah.
A lake...?
I don't remember such a large lake
in this area...?
What's this lake called?
I think it's just some bomb crater.
Where should we land?
Well, that's Mid Lake over there.
Take us down there.
There are some habitable structures.
Okay, let's land.
Yes, sir!
Commence operation!
Okay!
This won't take long.
Hey, look! What's going on?
Are you all right?!
It's finally falling apart, thanks to you.
We'll make an emergency landing.
Roger!
Bobsun, come in. This is Big John.
It seems like our attacks
have had a delayed effect.
How unlucky for them.
Have surveillance keep an eye on it.
Yes, sir.
It troubles me.
What does?
One of the rotors has stopped.
I'm just being paranoid.
It's descending.
Make this look like an emergency landing.
I know.
I like this kind of mission.
Do you think we fooled them?
4 elderly, 2 women,
and 3 children. 9 in total...
So, they weren't here.
Who?
I thought they'd sneak aboard some soldiers.
We're monitoring them closely.
There's no way they could do it.
You're right.
We thought we'd go to
those houses we saw earlier.
Are you sure you want to go to St. Anges?
It's not too far from here.
If St. Anges is gone...
then we will be back to join you.
Excuse me.
Where are that mother and child going?
There's nothing in that direction.
Captain! Look!
The pilot and crew have ejected and
are headed for the White Base.
I'll follow them!
All right, Amuro. They fell for it!
Mobile Suit
Did you see that?!
That's enough. I'm taking a little detour.
Worried about that mother and child?
You'll get in trouble.
Captain Garma is still young.
He wouldn't understand the feelings
of family men like us.
Right, let's go!
What's wrong, Mr. Ryu?
They're coming back!
What?!
Hey, where are they going?
Mr. Ryu, please hurry
and open up the container.
All right, Amuro. You go hide in the lake.
When the operation begins,
you'll be behind enemy lines and...
Hey! Amuro! Where are you going?!
Don't use the radio!
The enemy patrol craft is following
that mother and child. Aren't you worried?
Amuro!
Did it go well?
We don't know.
We'll find out in about 15 minutes.
All right, Kai.
Are you confident about trying this?
Yeah. I've seen the terrain of the battlefield.
We can do it.
Right! Guncannon and Guntank,
prepare for launch!
Yes, sir!
Help me, darling! Save my Coaly!
There they are!
I hope you don't notice me.
Hm?
See something?
I saw a flash. Let's check it out.
Missile safety, off.
Damn! He saw me!
The Federation mobile suit?
If only you hadn't found me.
Reduce throttle!
Yes, sir!
Big John has stopped transmitting!
What happened?
Forget the patrol craft.
Let's begin our attack!
Can't you reduce altitude a bit, Ms. Sayla?
Not possible.
If we go any lower,
we won't be able to move.
Do the best you can, Mr. Kai.
I'll try, Ms. Sayla.
I landed!
T-They're firing at me!
l-It's so powerful...!
I-I'll get you! I'll get you!
Giyal! See it?!
There's a new mobile suit to the right,
behind the Trojan Horse.
Cover me!
I'm out of ammo!
So, we're attacking the Trojan Horse
with our backs to the lake.
Yes, sir. The Blackjacks on the left flank
have moved another 3 km.
Garma, move the Blackjacks
with their backs to the lake...
...in front of the Trojan Horse.
Why? I believe it's only a matter of time
until the Trojan Horse falls.
The transport that crashed at the lake...
...is hiding a mobile suit.
That's what I would do.
Char!
We never checked
what was in that transport.
A mobile suit from behind the left flank!
What?!
I-Impossible!
A-Amuro!
It's the Gundam!
It's going according to plan.
Amuro's attacking from behind.
Good. The White Base will
concentrate all fire forward.
Destroy the Magella Attacks directly in front!
No! We'll be hitting our own!
Hold your fire!
I won't let you!
Wonder how the fightings going.
Who knows who'll win.
No matter who wins or loses...
...it'll mean that there will be
many more widows like me.
Have you fallen asleep, Coaly?
Even if I'm in the Gundam,
how can I fight all of those Zakus?!
Even I can do this much!
Kai!
It's another mobile suit!
They got the last Zaku!
Commander! Please respond!
Commander!
The Magella Attacks are wiped out!
None of them are functional!
Retreat! Retreat!
How can I possibly explain
this devastating failure to my sister?
You'll have a chance to redeem yourself.
Besides... we commanders have a duty
to boost morale on the front line.
Next time, I'll go too.
Th-Thank you.
We must return to our unit.
You should rest tonight in the capsule.
Thank you.
Hey, kid. Grow up big and strong
and protect your mother, okay?
Goodbye.
Madam...
Y-Yes?
Until a year ago, this was St. Anges.
I think it'll be for the best
if you join the others by the lake.
What?! This was...
This was...
St. Anges...?!
Coaly...!
Mommy...
I wonder if that mother and child
made it to St. Anges?
Garma Zabi personally launches
a vengeful attack on the White Base.
A battle-weary Amuro
reluctantly fights in the Gundam...
...and finally engages in an aerial battle.
Neither of them realize Char's intricate plot.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Fly, Gundam!
Next Time
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...